Guide to the Irving Fisher Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- MICROFILM INVENTORY
  - Economic Essays, Vol. XVIII: "Reflation" (, 1931 - 1933
    - Testimony before Senate Com. on Finance, 1933 March (Box 5)
    - "Inflation" ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1933 May 1 (Box 5)
    - "Mills, Glass are Wrong" ( Register, N.H., Ct.), 1933 May 3 (Box 5)
    - "Hails Step toward Reflation" ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1933 May 8 (Box 5)
    - "Explains 'Reflation'" ( Farmer, Columbia, Mo.), 1933 May 15 (Box 5)
    - Letter to editor re Gold & Wealth ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1933 May 22 (Box 5)
    - Letter to editor explaining Compensated Dollar and Tabular Standard ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1933 June 3 (Box 5)
    - "Lauds Reflation" ( Bulletin, Prov. R.I.), 1933 June 29 (Box 5)
      - Editorial re same ( Times, Fairmont, W. Va.), 1933 July 1 (Box 5)
    - "Money Policy Hailed as Epochal" ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1933 July 7 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Register, New Haven, Ct.), 1933 July 7 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Star, Johannesburg, S.A.), 1933 July 14 (Box 5)
    - Account of talk on Reflation ( Globe-Democrat, Globe-Democrat, St. Louis, Mo.), 1933 July 13 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Herald, Bridgeport, Ct.), 1933 July 16 (Box 5)
    - Interview, full of errors, 7 columns ( Herald, Bridgeport, Ct.), 1933 July 16 (Box 5)
    - Letter to Editor re Stabilization ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1933 July 20 (Box 5)
    - Account of talk before Amer. Asso. for Advancement of Science, Chicago ( News, Detroit, Mich.), 1933 July 20 (Box 5)
    - "Urges Curb on Margin Trading" ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1933 July 21 (Box 5)
      - Same
        - Register, New Haven, Ct., 1933 July 21 (Box 5)
        - News, Detroit, Mich., 1933 July 21 (Box 5)
        - Courant, Hartford, Ct., 1933 July 23 (Box 5)
        - Item, New Orleans, La., 1933 July 23 (Box 5)
    - "Roosevelt's Dollar Objective" ( The Bank Director, New York), 1933 August (Box 5)
    - "When Inflation is NOT Inflation" ( Liberty, N.Y.C.), 1933 September 16 (Box 5)
      - Reprint of same ( Printer's Ink ), 1933 October 5 (Box 5)
    - "The Managed Dollar" ( The World Today, N.Y.C.), 1933 October (Box 5)
      - Reprint of same in leaflet form, 1933 (Box 5)
    - "Views on Inflation," in symposium ( Literary Digest, New York), 1933 October 7 (Box 5)
    - "Says N.R.A. Has Failed" ( Register, N.H., Ct.), 1933 October 12 (Box 5)
    - Spanish clipping re interview with Calles, Mexico, 1933 (Box 5)
    - Spanish account of talk before Mexican Bankers Asso. ( Excelsior, Mexico, D.F.), 1933 October 19 (Box 5)
      - Full text of same (mimeo), 1933 (Box 5)
    - NANA Release re Interview with Calles, 1933 October 20 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Times, New York), 1933 October 19 (Box 5)
      - Same release ( Register, New Haven, Ct.), 1933 October 20 (Box 5)
      - Similar release ( Times, Oklahoma City, Okla.), 1933 October 20 (Box 5)
    - Advance notice of article to appear in Eve. Standard, London, Circa 1933 October 24 (Box 5)
      - Similar advance notice from Echo, Liverpool, 1933 October 20 (Box 5)
    - "Roosevelt's Money Plan Explained" ( Eve. Standard, London, Eng.), 1933 October 25 (Box 5)
    - "The Debt-Deflation Theory of Great Depressions," 21st Session of International Institute of Statistique, Mexico, 1933 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Econometrica ), 1933 October (Box 5)
      - Same, in Italian, Milan, Italy, 1933 (Box 5)
    - Testimony before Senate Banking & Currency Com. Wash., D.C., 1932 May 13, 18 (Box 5)
  - Economic Essays, Vol. XIX: "Reflation", 1933 - 1935
    - Spanish trans. of "The Debt Deflation Theory of Great Depressions" ( El Trimestre Economico, Mexico), 1934 (Box 5)
      - Same
        - Reprint in English, The Consensus, 1934 January (Box 5)
        - Polish trans., Prezglad Wspolczesny, 1934 May (Box 5)
        - Greek trans., Review of Social & Public Economics, 1934 August (Box 5)
        - English trans. of Loverdos' Introduction (Box 5)
    - "The American Dollar" ( Alumni Bulletin, American Univ. of Beirut), 1933 November 1 (Box 5)
    - "Buy Needed Supplies" ( Journal, Rochester), 1933 November 3 (Box 5)
      - Same (Box 5)
        - Post, Denver, Colo., 1933 November 3 (Box 5)
        - Bee News, Omaha, Neb., 1933 November 3 (Box 5)
        - Times-Union, Albany, N.Y., 1933 November 3 (Box 5)
        - American, Boston, Mass., 1933 November 3 (Box 5)
        - News, Baltimore, Md., 1933 November 3 (Box 5)
        - Georgian, Atlanta, Ga., 1933 November 4 (Box 5)
        - Plain Dealer, Cleveland, O., 1933 November 18 (Box 5)
    - Proposes Commodity Dollar ( Daily Princetonian ), 1933 November 8 (Box 5)
    - "Urges 50 cent Dollar" ( Journal, N.Y.C.), 1933 November 10 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Star Eagle, Newark, N.J.), 1933 November 11 (Box 5)
    - "Quotes Calles on Money" ( World-Telegram ), 1933 November 15 (Box 5)
      - Similar item ( Times, London, Eng.), 1933 November 16 (Box 5)
    - "Scores Money Critics" ( Register, N.H., Ct.), 1933 November 21 (Box 5)
    - "Defends Roosevelt Plan" ( Herald-Tribune ), 1933 November 23 (Box 5)
      - Similar item ( Christian Science Monitor ), 1933 November 25 (Box 5)
    - "Effect of F.D.R. Policy on Prices" ( System & Business Management ), 1933 December (Box 5)
    - "Says Gold is Baloney Money" ( Public Ledger ), 1933 December 3 (Box 5)
    - "Urges Support for Pres." ( Times Union, Albany), 1933 December 10 (Box 5)
    - "Backs Roosevelt on Dollar Plan" ( Knickerbocker Press ), 1933 (Box 5)
    - On "Money Illusion" ( Democrat, Olathe, Kan.), 1933 December 14 (Box 5)
    - Editorial re 15 Professors ( Times, Hartford), 1933 December 18 (Box 5)
    - "Lists 18 Money Experts" ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1933 December 26 (Box 5)
      - Editorial re same ( Times [?]), 1933 December 27 (Box 5)
      - "Treadway Assails Fisher List", 1933 (Box 5)
      - Editorial re same ( Journal-Courier ), 1933 December 27 (Box 5)
    - "Are Booms & Depressions Transmitted Internationally Through Monetary Standards?," International Institute of Statistics, 1934 (Box 5)
    - Testimony at House Hearings, 1934 February 1 (Box 5)
    - "Reflation and Stabilization," also Discussion of Warburg paper ( The Annals, Amer. Acad. of Polit. and Social Science, Phila., Pa.), 1934 (Box 5)
    - "Farm Prices Under Inflation" ( Farm Journal ), 1934 January (Box 5)
    - "Backs F.D.R. Monetary Policies" ( The Right Angle ), 1934 January (Box 5)
      - Similar item ( American ), 1934 January 1 (Box 5)
    - "Commends Money Isolation" ( Times ), 1934 January 7 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Herald-Tribune ), 1934 January 7 (Box 5)
    - "The President & the Price Level" ( Foreword Together, Chicago, Ill.), 1934 February (Box 5)
    - "59 cent Dollar Misleading" ( Post-Star ), 1934 February 21 (Box 5)
    - "Is Mr. Roosevelt Consistent?" ( Business Bulletin, College of City of N.Y.), 1934 March (Box 5)
    - "Henry W. Farnam" ( Amer. Econ. Review ), 1934 March (Box 5)
    - Views on New Dollar ( Telegram, Worcester), 1934 March 2 (Box 5)
    - "Hopes F.D.R. to Avert Auto Strike ( Tribune, Minneapolis), 1934 March 21 (Box 5)
    - "Assails Russian Ways of New Dealers" ( Tribune, Chicago, Ill.), 1934 April 20 (Box 5)
    - "Need for 100 cent Dollar" ( La Salle St. Journal, Chicago. Ill.), 1934 April 20 (Box 5)
    - "New Deal Too Radical" ( Herald-Examiner ), 1934 April 20 (Box 5)
    - Editorial ( Star Courier, Kewanee, Ill.), 1934 April 23 (Box 5)
    - Quote re "Rubber Dollar" ( Women's Wear ), 1934 April 24 (Box 5)
    - Editorial ( Journal, Stevens Point, Wis.), 1934 April 24 (Box 5)
    - "Urges Action to Free Bank Deposits" ( American, New York), 1934 April 26 (Box 5)
    - "Urges More Devaluation" ( Investment News ), 1934 April 26 (Box 5)
    - Re N.R.A. ( Review, Alliance, O.), 1934 November 9 (Box 5)
    - "Urges Reflation" ( Dispatch ), 1934 November 9 (Box 5)
    - "Recovery Lag under N.R.A." ( Standard Examiner, Ogden, Utah), 1934 November 9 (Box 5)
    - Re Relief Bill ( Wisconsin News ), 1935 April 9 (Box 5)
    - "Business Gains" ( Journal, Milwaukee), 1935 April 9 (Box 5)
    - "Labor Has Greatest Stake in Program" ( Leader, Milwaukee, Wis.), 1935 April 9 (Box 5)
    - "Condemns Crop Control" ( Sentinel, Milwaukee), 1935 April 10 (Box 5)
    - "Country Needs More Money" ( Wis. News Finance, Milwaukee), 1935 April 10 (Box 5)
    - "Thinks Depression Overcome" ( Light, San Antonio, Texas), 1935 May 23 (Box 5)
    - "Flays Bonus Bill" ( Light ), 1935 May 23 (Box 5)
    - Same as above item from Light ( News, San Antonio), 1935 May 23 (Box 5)
      See also: series 7, reel 5, volume 19
    - "Believes Slump Passing" ( World-Telegram ), 1935 May 23 (Box 5)
    - "Recovery is Near" ( Times, New York), 1935 May 24 (Box 5)
    - "Answers Questions" ( Trust Companies ), 1935 July (Box 5)
    - "3 Different Prices of Silver Hit" ( Post-Gazette, Pittsburgh), 1935 August 12 (Box 5)
      - Same ( Review, Decatur, Ill.), 1935 August 18 (Box 5)
    - "Basic Principle of Wages" ( Republican, Springfield, Mass.), 1935 August 19 (Box 5)
    - Quote re Father Coughlin ( The Resurrection ), 1935 August (Box 5)
    - "Check Book Money Provides New Buying Power" ( Times-Press, Akron, O.), 1935 September 16 (Box 5)
    - re Testimony before House Currency Com. ( Times, Buffalo, N.Y.), 1935 September 17 (Box 5)
    - "Rise of 18 Billion in '36 Income" ( Times ), 1935 September 18 (Box 5)
    - re Open Market Operation of Federal Reserve Board ( Citizen, Columbus, O.), 1935 September 18 (Box 5)
    - "Bank Act New Deal's Most Constructive Step" ( Press, Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1935 September 18 (Box 5)
    - "The Mind of Mr. Eccles" ( Tribune, Alberqueque), 1935 September 24 (Box 5)
    - "Govt. Deeply in Business by Slump" ( Republican, Waterbury, Ct.), 1935 September 30 (Box 5)
    - "Urges High Reserves" ( Herald-Tribune ), 1935 October 13 (Box 5)
    - "Money is Govt. Function" ( Times, Indianapolis, Ind.), 1935 October 16 (Box 5)
    - "Speaks at Lehigh Valley Conference" ( Call, Allentown, Pa.), 1935 October 19 (Box 5)
    - Announcement of Nov 19 lecture ( State Journal, Lansing, Mich.), 1935 November 9 (Box 5)
      - Another ( State Journal ), 1935 November 18 (Box 5)
      - "Assails New Deal Policies" (same paper), 1935 November 20 (Box 5)
      - Similar item ( Journal, Lincoln, Neb.), 1935 November 21 (Box 5)
    - "Urges Swedish Money System" ( News, Chicago), 1935 November 22 (Box 5)
    - "Destruction Cannot Create Wealth" ( Herald-Examiner, Chicago, Ill.), 1935 November 23 (Box 5)
    - "Dollar Worth $1.16" ( Sentinel, Milwaukee, Wis.), 1935 November 26 (Box 5)
    - "Talks on Inflation" ( Journal, Milwaukee), 1935 November 27 (Box 5)
    - "Plans for Employment Relief" ( Times, Toledo), 1937 December 15 (Box 5)
    - "Pressure for Credit Expansion" ( Herald-Tribune, New York), 1935 December 31 (Box 5)
  - Economic Essays, Vol. XX: "Income Tax & Miscl.", 1932 - 1946
    - über Verfahrensweisen Zur Bestimmung des Geldlichen Grenznutzens, by Otto Weinberger, 1932 December (Box 5)
      See Part III, p 391, for discussion of I.F.'s "A Statistical Method for Measuring Marginal Utility and Testing the Justice of a Progressive Income Tax" (1927), in Zeitschrift Fur Die Gesamte Staatswissenschaft
    - "Income in Theory and Income Taxation in Practice," I-IV, 1936 Jul 7-10, ( Colorado College Publication, General Series No. 208, Studies Series No. 21), 1936 September (Box 5)
      - "The Depression, Its Causes and Cures,", reprinted in same pamphlet with preceding item, 1936 July 10 (Box 5)
      - "Income in Theory and Income Taxation in Practice," expanded paper from same ( Econometrica, Vol. 5, No. 1), 1937 January (Box 5)
      - Comments re same by Angelos Angelopoulos ( Review of, Social & Financial Economics, 5th Yr., No. 3), 1936 September - December (Box 5)
    - "A Practical Schedule for an Income Tax" ( The Tax Magazine, Chicago, Vol. 15, No. 7), 1937 July (Box 5)
      - Same, reprinted in The Accountant, London, Eng., Supplement, 1937 November 6 (Box 5)
    - "A General View of the Income Tax" ( Cornell Law, Quarterly, Ithaca, N.Y., Vol. XXIII, No. 1), 1937 December (Box 5)
    - "A Simplified Income Tax Schedule" ( Nation's Business, New York), 1938 February (Box 5)
    - "Double Taxation of Savings" ( American Economic Review, Vol. XXIX, No. 1), 1939 March (Box 5)
    - "The Concepts of Income: A Rebuttal" ( Econometrica, Vol. 7, No. 4), 1939 October (Box 5)
    - "Tax Bill Change Suggested," letter to Editor ( Times, New York), 1940 September 9 (Box 5)
    - "A Fundamental Reason for Not Taxing Savings" ( Taxes, Chicago, Vol. 19, No. 1), 1941 January (Box 5)
    - "I.F. Says death of Gov. Strong Aided Nazis" ( Times, Los Angeles, Calif.), 1941 January 30 (Box 5)
    - Article & Editorial re. I.F.'s. joining Faculty of Univ. of So. Cal. ( Daily Trojan ), 1941 February 6 (Box 5)
    - Rebuttal, re articles by Prof. Hewett and Mr. Benjamin on Taxing Savins in same issue ( Taxes ), 1941 May (Box 5)
    - Statement at Hearings on Revenua Act of 1941 ) (Box 5)
    - "A Second Reason for Not Taxing Savings" ( Taxes, Chicago), 1941 August (Box 5)
    - "Urges Untaxing of Savings," account of address to Iowa Bankers Asso. ( American Banker, N.Y.C.), 1942 October 27 (Box 5)
      - Extract from same ( Trusts & Estates, N.Y.C.), 1942 December (Box 5)
    - "The Spendings Tax," testimony before Senate Fin. Com., 1942 August 14 (Box 5)
    - Rebuttal to Prof. Crum and Mr. Musgrave's articles on Taxation of Savings in 1939 Sep issue ( American Economic Review, Vol. XXXII, No. 1), 1942 March (Box 5)
    - "Paradoxes in Taxing Savings" ( Econometrica ), 1942 April (Box 5)
    - "Income Tax Revision," Reply to Prof. Hotelling ( Econometrica ), 1943 January (Box 5)
    - Mimeo of Radio Address: "Taxes & Savings", 1943 May or June (Box 5)
    - Mimeo of Statement on Tax Bill before House Committee on Ways and Means, 1943 October 11 (Box 5)
      - Mimeo of Statement re same before Senate Com. on Finance, 1943 December 3 (Box 5)
      - Statement re same at Congressional Hearing, 1944 (Box 5)
    - "Tax on Spending Urged" ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1944 March (Box 5)
    - "A Proposed Spendings Tax" ( Commercial & Financial Chronicle, N.Y.C.), 1944 April 6 (Box 5)
    - "Constructive Income Taxation," address before Federal Bar Tax Institute, ( Vital Speeches of the Day, N.Y.C., Vol. X, No. 15), 1944 March 231944 May 15 (Box 5)
    - "How Can We Pay the National Debt?" Report of, Conference at Penn. State College), 1944 June 5-6 (Box 5)
    - "Against Capital Gains Tax," letter to Editor ( Times, New York), 1945 April 4 (Box 5)
    - "Revision of Income Taxes" ( Tax Topics, Nat'l Convention of Accountants Number, Los Angeles), 1945 June (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous
      - "The Single Tax," reprint of article written for in The International Musician, New York, Vol. XXXII, No. 6, 1932 Sep1932 November - December (Box 5)
      - Advance notice of address before Penna. Newspaper Publishers Asso. ( Bulletin, Harrisburg), 1932 December 24 (Box 5)
        See also: series 7, reel 9, volume 33
      - "Comments on Capitalism" ( Common Sense, N.Y.C.), 1933 February 2 (Box 5)
      - "Townsend Plan Scored," YMCA Talk ( Union, Springfield, Mass.), 1936 January 13 (Box 5)
        - Similar talk ( Herald, Grand Rapids, Mich.), 1936 March 12 (Box 5)
      - "If I Were Dictator" ( News, Detroit, Mich.), 1936 January 5 (Box 5)
      - "Better Tone in Europe" ( Christian Science Monitor, Boston, Mass.), 1936 October 28 (Box 5)
      - "A Simple Method for Calculating 'Distributed Lag,'" in French ( Bulletin, of International Statistical Institute, Vol. XXIX, 1st Liv., (1936) Athens (Box 5)
      - Reply to Question in Symposium on Undistributed Profits Tax ( The Wharton Review, Phila.), 1936 June (Box 5)
      - "Changes in the Wholesale Price Index in Relation to Factory Employment" ( Journal of the American Statistical Asso.), 1936 September (Box 5)
      - "Do High Wages Make Prosperity?" correspondence with Edward A. Filene ( The Forum, Concord, N.H.), 1936 October (Box 5)
      - "Attributes Business Decline to Bad Banking" ( Social Justice, Father Coughlin's Weekly, Royal Oak, Mich.), 1936 November 16 (Box 5)
      - "Curb on War Seen in Stable Moneys" ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1936 November 8 (Box 5)
        - Same (fuller) ( News, Dallas, Texas), 1936 November 8 (Box 5)
      - "Note on a Short-Cut Method for Calculating Distributed Lags" ( Bulletin of International Statistical Institute, Tome XXIX, 3 Liv.), 1937 (Box 5)
      - Review of "Is There Enough Gold?," by Charles O. Hardy ( Journal of Amer. Statistical Asso.), 1937 March (Box 5)
      - Answer to Question of the Week ( U.S. News ), 1937 May 3 (Box 5)
        - Same, reprinted ( News, Onstead, Mich.), 1937 May 13 (Box 5)
      - Review of "The Mathematical Problem of the Price Index," by J. K. Montgomery ( Journal of, Amer. Statistical Asso.), 1937 December (Box 5)
      - "New War Debt Settlement Plan Proposed" ( N.Y. Herald, Paris, France), 1938 June 27 (Box 5)
      - "Cournot Forty Years Ago" ( Econometrica ), 1938 July (Box 5)
      - Book Review of "Common-Stock, Indexes, 1871-1937," by Alfred Cowles 3d and Associates ( Journal of, Polit. Economy), 1939 June (Box 5)
      - Summary of paper on "A Three -Dimensional Representation of the Factors of Production," p 181 in Report of the Detroit Meeting, 1938 Dec 27-30 ( Econometrica, Vol. 7, No. 2), 1939 April (Box 5)
        - Full Text of same ( Econometrica, Vol. 7, No. 4), 1939 October (Box 5)
      - "The Velocity of Circulation of Money," (Report of 6th Annual Research Conference on Econ. & Statistics, Colorado Springs), 1940 July (Box 5)
      - "Mathematical Method in the Social Sciences" ( Econometrica, Vol. 9, Nos. 3 & 4), 1941 July - October (Box 5)
      - "Velocity of the Circulation of Money", 1946 April (Box 5)
      - "The Spendings Tax in Peace and War," by Wm. Vickrey, and "Distribution Taxation: a Rejoinder," by Irving Fisher ( Columbia Law Review ), 1943 June (Box 5)
  - Economic Essays, Vol. XXI: "100% Money", 1934 - 1945
    - "Defends Monetary Aims of New Dealers" ( Herald Tribune, New York), 1934 September 19 (Box 5)
    - "N.R.A. Is Monopoly" ( Journal of Commerce ), 1934 September 19 (Box 5)
    - "Banks 100% Liquid, I.F.'s Aim" ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1934 September 19 (Box 5)
    - "100% Check Money Urged" ( Investment News ), 1934 September 19 (Box 5)
      - Editorial on same ( Wall St. Journal ), 1934 September 20 (Box 5)
      - Editorial reprinted ( News Bureau, Boston), 1934 September 21 (Box 5)
      - Letter to Editor, answering editorial ( Wall St. Journal ), 1934 October 9 (Box 5)
      - Similar letter to Editor ( News Bureau ), 1934 October 10 (Box 5)
      - Inflation?--After the Bonus, talk before Alexander Forum Foundation, (N.Y.C.), 1934 November 301934 September 28 (Box 5)
    - "Tells Controllers of Monetary Cure for Depression" ( The Controller, New York), 1934 October (Box 5)
      - Reprint of portions of same, 1934 (Box 5)
    - Advance notice of following article ( Rotarian ), 1934 September (Box 5)
      - "Some A B C's of Modern Money" ( Rotarian ), 1934 October (Box 5)
      - Rebuttal to foregoing by James E. Boyle ( Rotarian ), 1934 December (Box 5)
    - "Adverse comments re 100% Money" ( American Banker, N.Y.C.), 1934 October 18 (Box 5)
      - Letter to Editor, answering foregoing, 1934 December 7 (Box 5)
    - "Our Monetary Policy" ( Premier Rayon Review, Cleveland, Ohio), 1935 January (Box 5)
    - "100% Reserve Plan Developing Strong Support" ( Wall St. Journal ), 1935 February 19 (Box 5)
    - "Withold Oppostion to Banking Bill in fear of 100% Reserves Plan" ( Herald Tribune, New York), 1935 February 25 (Box 5)
    - Italian trans. of Ch. I, Milan 100% Money ), 1935 March (Box 5)
    - "A Few Things Wrong with 100% Reserve Plan," in column ( Journal ), 1935 March (Box 5)
      - Letter to Editor, replying to foregoing, 1935 March 23 (Box 5)
    - Asso. Press account of WOR address on 100% Plan, 1935 October 13 (Box 5)
    - "Urges Denuding Bankers of Power" ( Republican, Springfield, Mass.), 1936 January 13 (Box 5)
    - "Revise Banking Law, Urges" ( Post, N.Y.C.), 1936 January 27 (Box 5)
    - "100% Money Again" ( Social Research, N.Y.C.), 1936 May (Box 5)
    - "100% Money & the Public Debt" Economic Forum ), 1936 Spr. (Box 5)
      - Spanish trans. of same ( Revue of Economic & Statistics, Mexico), 1936 June (Box 5)
    - "100% Dollar Urged" ( Bulletin, Phila., Pa.), 1936 June 10 (Box 5)
    - "The Bankers' Interest in 100% Money" ( The Bankers' Magazine, N.Y.C.), 1936 October (Box 5)
    - "100%iges Geld and die Staatsschuld," German Review of "100% Money" by Von Dr. Franz Hochstetter ( Schule der Freiheit, Berlin, Germany), 1936 December 1 (Box 5)
    - Letter to the Editor, replying to discussion of 100% Money in Dec issue ( Bankers Magazine ), 1937 February (Box 5)
    - "100% Reserves: An Old System Adopted to Meet Modern Needs" ( The Searchlight, Newark, N.J.), 1937 February (Box 5)
    - "100% Money and Branch Flanking" ( American Banker ), 1937 March 24 (Box 5)
      - Same, reprinted ( Mountain States Banker ), 1937 March (Box 5)
      - Same, reprinted ( Northwestern Banker ), 1937 March (Box 5)
    - "Bank Reserves," letter to Editor, replying to article, by A. V. Barber in Dec issue ( The Banker, London, Eng.), 1937 May (Box 5)
    - "Note Suggested by Review of 100% Money" ( Journal of Royal Statistical Society, Vol. C, Part II), 1937 (Box 5)
    - Reprint of Searchlight item above ( Commercial & Financial Chronicle, Los Angeles, Calif.), 1937 June (Box 5)
      See also: series 7, reel 5, volume 21
    - Article by A. V. Barber, replying to I.F.'s letter in May issue ( The Banker, London), 1937 June (Box 5)
    - German trans. of Foreword to "100% Money" ( Post-Zoll-n & Te1egraphen Zeitung, Burgdorf, Germany), 1937 August 19 (Box 5)
    - Greek trans. of "100% Money" by Alexander Loverdos, Trapezitike, Athens
      - 1st installment, 1935 September 7 (Box 5)
      - 2nd installment, 1935 October 7 (Box 5)
      - 5th installment, 1936 January 7 (Box 5)
      - 6th installment, 1936 February 7 (Box 5)
      - 7th installment, 1936 March 7 (Box 5)
      - 8th installment, 1936 May 7 (Box 5)
      - 9th installment, 1936 June 7 (Box 5)
      - 9th A installment, 1936 August 7 (Box 5)
      - 10th installment, 1936 September 7 (Box 5)
      - 11th installment, 1936 October 7 (Box 5)
      - 14th installment, 1936 January 7 (Box 5)
    - "The Principle of 100% Reserves" ( Dynamic America ), New York), 1938 July (Box 5)
      - Letter to Editor, replying to Dr. Spahr's criticism of preceding item ( Dynamic America ), 1938 September (Box 5)
    - Account of talk to Minnesota Bankers on 100% Money ( Tribune, Minneapolis, Minn.), 1938 October 14 (Box 5)
    - "One Hundred Per Cent Reserves Back of demand Deposits Would Prevent Booms and Depressions," reprint of Radio dialogue with Senator Norris 1939 Mar 7, included as Extension of Remarks by Hon. Jerry Voorhis in the Congressional Record, Appendix, Vol. 84, Part 11, p 977 ( Catholic Tribune, Dubuque, Iowa), 1939 April 5 (Box 5)
    - "Why Banks Could Make More Money Under 100% Reserve System" ( American Banker, New York), 1943 January 6 (Box 5)
    - "Answers to Objections to the 100% Plan", 1946 (Box 5)
  - Economic Essays, Vol. XXII: "Monetary Theory", 1935 - 1947
    - "High Value Seen in Gold Case" ( Times, Toledo), 1935 January 28 (Box 6)
    - "What Is Sound Money?," WHN address, ( Vital Speeches of the Day, N.Y.C.), 1934 November 71935 February (Box 6)
    - "Stabilizing Currencies," letter to Editor ( Times, New York), 1935 February 2 (Box 6)
    - Statement on Proposed Banking Act of 1935 (Steagall), release of Com. for Nation, (Mimeo), 1935 February 11 (Box 6)
      - Same
        - Herald-Tribune, New York, 1935 February 11 (Box 6)
        - American, New York, 1935 February 11 (Box 6)